Guide to the Grace Donald and Ezra Caryl Brownell letters, 1918-1921
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Grace Donald and Ezra Caryl Brownell letters 1918-1921
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Brownell, Grace Donald
0.5 Linear Feet 254 Items
Ezra Caryl Brownell, of Ridgefield Park, New Jersey was a banker with the Bank of New York. In 1918 he was made manager of the Tientsin, China branch of the Asia Banking Corporation and was charged with oversight of the bank's opening. He travelled to China in April 1918 with his wife Grace Donald Brownell of Butler, New Jersey. The couple lived in Shanghai and Tientsin, returning to the United States in March 1921.
Chiefly letters of Grace Donald Brownell to family members and family friends in New Jersey. Letters of Ezra Carly Brownell are scattered throughout the collection. The letters touch on myriad topics including familial events and happenings in New Jersey; observations of Chinese and Japanese customs and culture; current affairs in China, the United States, and the world; as well as the couples' travels, routines, and other activities in China.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Grace Donald and Ezra Caryl Brownell letters were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2008.
Biographical Note
Grace Donald Brownell was born 28 February 1893 at Butler, New Jersey and eventually married Ezra Caryl Brownell. Ezra, or Caryl as he was known to friends, family, and colleagues, was born in Brooklyn, New York on 21 December 1889 to Ezra and Caryle Brownell. The couple resided in Ridgefield Park, NJ. In August 1918 Ezra was hired by the Asia Banking Corporation to manage the corporation's branch in Tientsen, China. The couple travelled by train from New Jersey to San Francisco in the fall of 1918 making stops in Provo, Denver, and Salt Lake City. The couple boarded the S.S. Nanking in September 1918 making stops in Honalulu and Yokohama, Japan before arriving at Beijing in October 1918. While settling into life in Beijing the couple toured other foreign concessions and various Beijing neighborhoods, took day trips to other nearby cities, attended church services of numerous denominations, and socialized with other western and native Chinese families. The couple remained in Beijing until May 1919 when Ezra moved to Tientsen to begin preparations for the bank's grand opening before joined by Grace in June. In January 1921 the couple bagan making preparations for the return journey planning stops in Japan, Sri Lanka, Yemen, Egypt, Italy, France, and the British Isles en route to the United States. The couple eventually settled in Oradell, Bergen County, New Jersey.
Collection Overview
The collection consits primarily of letters written by Grace Donald Brownell to friends and family in New Jersey. However, also present are scattered letters of Ezra Carly Brownell.
Letters of 1918 primarily describe the couple's journey from New Jersey to San Francisco and the voyage to China on the S.S. Nanking. Present are descriptions of the cities of Salt Lake City and Provo, Utah, including a visit to the Great Salt Lake and San Francisco, California. Letters also describe the voyage from San Francisco to Shanghai including missionaries, Y.M.C.A workers, schoolteachers, and Red Cross workers aboard the S.S. Nanking; stops in Honalulu, Hawaii and Yokohama, Japan. Letters also offer observations of Japanese and Chinese cultures, the laboring poor in China, the effects of embargo on the native population, and differences in local dress based on class and gender.
Letters of 1919 offer descriptions of life in Beijing and Tientsen, China. Letters prior to the couples' relocation to Tientsen describe visits to a local convent, orphanage, tea house, market, and temple; preparations for and celebrations of the Chinese New Year; modes of Chinese worship and perceived "superstitions"; and activities with the local Woman's Club. Letters from Tientsen include detailed descriptions of the couples' home and furnishings, Bastille Day celebrations in the local French settlement, the activities and services of various religious denominations including the Church of England, Union Church, Catholic Church and Christian Science, meetings with numerous diplomats and dignitaries including the American, British, and Prussian Consuls and the Chinese Commissioner of Foreign Affairs, as well as Grace's teaching position at a Methodist Mission School.
Letters of 1920 and 1921 continue to focus on the couples' daily life in Tientsen including various club activities, trips into the country side, the cost of goods, services, and various commodities, and descriptions of a visit to a Womens Temple. Many of the letters, however, discuss social and political developments in China including student demonstrations and unrest, the boycott of Japanese goods, and the beginning of factionalism within the military mentioning General Wu Peifu of the Zhili clique and accusations of other factions collaborating with the Japanese. Letters also describe the influx of refugees into Tientsen from the provinces due to famine and factional fighting and various foreign relief efforts.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Brownell, Ezra Caryl
Brownell, Grace Donald
Wu, Peifu, 1874-1939
Bank of New York
Young Men's Christian Association (Beijing, China)
Methodist Church -- Missions
Missions -- China
Beijing (China) -- Social life and customs
China -- History -- 1912-1928
China -- History -- Warlord Period, 1916-1928
China -- Social conditions -- 1912-1949
China -- Social life and customs -- 1912-1949
Tientsin, China (Japanese Concession)
Related Material
Paul Hibbert Clyde and Mary (Kestler) Clyde Papers, 1924-2001 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Sidney Gamble Photographs, 1906-2007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Grace Donald and Ezra Caryl Brownell letters, 1918-1921, (1 box)
  - Letters, 1918 April-October (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1918 November-December (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1919 January-February (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1919 March-April (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1919 May-July (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1919 August-September (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1919 October-December (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1920 January-March (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1920 April-June (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1920 July-September (Box 1)
  - Letters, 1920 October-1921 March and undated (Box 1)
  - Print Material, 1918-1919 and undated (Box 1)